阿富汗南部坎大哈省
Kandahar Province, southern Afghanistan,
塔利班的老巢
the birthplace of the Taliban.
在這五萬四千平方米的地方裡充斥著野蠻的暴力
It's 54,000 square kilometres of brutal insurgency,
衝突,種族對抗還有血腥屠殺
conflicting agendas, tribal rivalry and blood feuds.
我們是加拿大特種部隊
This is the Canadian Forces' area of operation. We wear it.
每天,我們都要深入到
And every day, we drive deeper
敵人的心腹之地
into the furnace of enemy country.
這是一條通向地獄的不歸路
It's one hell of a rough road.
阿爾法39,這裡是66號
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66.
66號,這裡是阿爾法39
66, this is Three Niner Alpha. Send. Over.
66號,發現情況
66. I have contact. Over.
阿爾法39.收到
Three Niner Alpha, roger.
左邊15度,一個人
About 15 left to one.
風速15到20.風向向右
Wind gusts 15 to 20. Left to right.
一個左撇子老頭
Old left-hand-sided target.
瞄準了
On.
這傢伙拿了把鐵鍬
The buddy's got a shovel.
- 也許是個農民 - 農民在路上?
- Could be a farmer. - On a road?
為什麼不可以呢?
Why not?
因為這是條路,夥計
'Cause it's a road, man.
也許是個很差勁的農民
Could be a real shitty farmer
誰會這樣,一直很迷惑不解的,你知道的?
who's, like, constantly puzzled, you know?
他在村子裡問"為什麼我的莊稼長得不行?"
He's in the village asking, "Why are my crops so lousy?"
大家都不忍心說"嘿,夥計...
And no one has the heart to say, "Hey, buddy...
你不能在公路上...
you can't grow, like...
種莊稼"
anything on a road."
你能閉嘴嗎?
Will you shut the fuck up?
情況不好.他拿著的很像是122mm的炸彈
Bad move. He's got a shell casing shaped like a 122,
有橘黃色引爆器的那種
orange det cord sticking out of the nose.
阿爾法39,這裡是66號
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66.
身份確認,反政府武裝人員
I have PID, positive ID on one times insurgent.
時間10:28
Time of contact 10:28 local.
66號,這裡是阿爾法39
66, this is Three Niner Alpha. Over.
阿爾法39,66號報告
Three Niner Alpha, 66. Sitrep.
反政府武裝人員,身穿灰色長衣
One times insurgent, grey man jams,
頭上裹著黑布, 手拿122mm炸彈
black head dress, holding a 122 mm shell casing
頂部有橘黃色引爆器
with orange det cord emanating from the top.
引爆器?
Emanating?
從頂部引出來的
Coming out of the top.
現在他正把炸彈放到鬣狗大路上的
And now he's placing the projectile into the hole.
一個洞裡.魁北克坐標北西北
One Road Hyena. 650 meters to the north-north-west
4176-8134 650米處
of grid Quebec Quebec 4176-8134.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, acknowledged.
當他後退時,開火
When he stands back up, engage.
準備好了
Standby.
幹掉他
Send it.
阿爾法39,66號
Three Niner Alpha, 66.
阿爾法39,擊斃了
Three Niner Alpha, send.
反政府武裝人員在路中間被擊斃.沒有再移動的跡象
One times insurgent engaged in centre mass. No motion.
魁北克坐標4176-8134
At grid Quebec Quebec 4176-8134.
準備到撤離點集合,魁北克坐標4199-8226
Moving to RV extraction at grid Quebec Quebec 4199-8226.
阿爾法39,收到,66號
Three Niner Alpha, roger that, 66.
反政府武裝人員
One times insurgent VSA.
我們進行高級別確認
We are pushing higher assets to confirm.
66號,收到.現在撤離
66, roger. Exfiling now.
阿爾法39,收到.你們在撤離
Three Niner Alpha, roger. Your ride's en route.
查理31,這裡是阿爾法39
Three One Charlie, this is Three Niner.
現在行動.查理31
Move now. Three One Charlie.
我們出發了.去10英里處接他們
We're on the move. Pick them up in 10 Mikes.
高級別確認:
Higher assets confirmation:
反政府武裝人員在魁北克坐標4176-8134處陣亡
one times insurgent KIA at grid Quebec Quebec 4176-8134.
怎麼回事?
What's up?
看看那邊的陰溝
Take a look at that culvert.
左邊50米處路面上有東西
Covers a stretch of road out 50 metres to the left.
查理31,這裡是66號.裝甲車在哪裡?
Three One Charlie, this is 66. What's your ETA?
66號,查理31.我們在山另一側,距離你們大約3到4英里
66, Three One Charlie. We're 3-4 Mikes the other side of the hill.
查理31.這裡是66號.你們先別動
Three One Charlie, this is 66. Advise you hold your position.
別越過小山.重複一遍,別越過小山
Do not crest the hill. I say again, do not crest the hill.
我們發現路上有情況
We've got something weird on the road.
要去看看,你們等一下
Gonna have a look. Wait out.
66號,查理31,收到
66, Three One Charlie. Good copy.
希基,用狙擊槍向陰溝左邊10米
Hickey, get the Coyote on the patch just 10 meters
路面補丁處,開一槍
left of that culvert, put a round in it.
你覺得呢?
What do you think?
絕對沒東西
It's probably nothing.
希基,再向另一個補丁處開一槍
Hickey, put a round in that patch next to it.
一定是公路的補丁修的不好
Could be just a bad patch of road.
- 如果你錯了呢? - 我什麼時候錯過啊?
- What if you're wrong? - When have I ever been wrong?
- 我姐姐 - 是的,太糟了
- My sister. - Yeah, that was bad.
希基,只是為了好玩
Hickey, just for fun, chamber up a Raufuss.
向我們面前的那個補丁再開一槍
Line up on that patch dead ahead of us.
讓我們看看到底會怎樣
Let's see what an incendiary does.
準備好了
Standby.
開火
Send it.
你沒事吧? 是的,靠!
You okay? Yeah. Fuck!
我們炸開了
We're blown.
- 有埋伏! - 走,走,走!
- Ambush! - Go, go, go!
- 走! 離開那裡! - 掩護!
- Go! Get the fuck outta there! - Covering!
- 走! - 掩護!
- Move it! - Covering!
掩護!
Covering!
- 快走! - 快走!
- Leaving! - Leaving!
阿爾法39,這裡是66號報告
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66. Sitrep.
我們遭到襲擊,正在撤離
We are being effectively engaged. Exfiling now. Over.
- 阿爾法39,收到.- 我們得到一個消息
- Three Niner Alpha, roger. Out. - We got a TIC,
我們的部隊遭遇襲擊
we got troops in contact.
查理31.查理31
Three One Charlie, Three Niner Alpha.
你收到66號的消息了嗎?
Did you acknowledge last from 66?
查理31.收到.現在出發
Three One Charlie, roger that. Moving out now.
66號.不行.不要越過小山
66. Negative. Do not crest the hill.
公路上有炸彈.你會遇襲的
The road is filled with IEDs. You're the target.
你能繞過山脊,在另一側接我們嗎?
Can you circle the ridge, get us on the back side?
查理31,收到
Three one Charlie, roger.
但是他們有20到25人
But it's two zero, two five Mikes at best.
等一下,66號,阿爾法39.他們的武裝情況如何?
Break Break. 66, Three Niner Alpha. What's the force size?
66號.20到25名武裝份子
66. Two zero to two five hostiles.
我們正在尋找有利的防守點
Am seeking strong point. Wait out.
靠!
Fuck!
- 他們還在追擊我們  - 靠!
- They're still on us! - Fuck!
- 我靠! - 他們要把我們幹掉了!
- Motherfucker! - They got us cut off!
我們需要找到一個有利的防守點
We need to find a strong point!
我看到到個村子!
I got a village!
66號,我們要去葡萄地
66, we're moving at the grape field.
那裡是有利的防守點
We'll strong-point from there. Wait out.
走!
Moving!
掩護!
Covering!
靠! 我們被封鎖了!
Fuck! We're blocked, we're blocked!
走那邊!
Go that way!
翻牆!快點!
Over the wall! Come on!
- 掩護! - 快走,坦克!
- Cover! - Go, Tank!
- 走啊! - 走,走,走!
- Let's go! - Go, go, go!
- 6點鐘方向! - 走,走,走!
- On my 6! - Go, go, go!
- 看見門了! - 走, 走!
- We got a door! - Move, move!
換子彈!
Changing mags!
- 注意後面! - 注意後面!
- Check your back! - Check your back!
掩護!
Covering!
- 掩護! - 掩護!
- Covering! - Covering!
坦克,希基,走啊!
Tank, Hickey, go!
走,走,走!
Go, go, go!
- 走,走! 阿奇! - 掩護! 走!
- Go, go! Argh! - Covering! Go!
- 前面就是門了! - 走!
- We got a door straight ahead! - Go!
靠! 鎖住了!
Fuck! It's blocked!
66號,阿爾法39.情況如何
66, Three Niner Alpha. Send sitrep. Over.
- 66號 - 掩護!
- 66. - Covering!
我們還在交戰中. 我們已經到了村子
We still have contact. We're moving into village,
馬上就會有合適的防守點了,發送坐標
will strong-point from there, Send grid, over.
- 盡快呼叫零點的裝甲車 - 夫人,已經連接零點
- Get Lavigne on Zero, ASAP. - You're with Zero, ma'am.
零點,這裡是阿爾法39
Zero, this is Three Niner Alpha.
我們的部隊在交戰.敵人規模:25名武裝份子
I've got troops in contact. Force size: two five insurgents.
請求快速空中支援
Request fast air. Over.
阿爾法39.這裡是零點.收到
Three Niner Alpha, this is Zero. Roger that.
我們要看一下能提供什麼空中支援
We'll see what we got in the air.
戰術空軍,有什麼飛機在飛嗎?
TAC-P, what lines are we flying right now?
- 有一架飛機,但不在範圍內 - 讓他過去,要快
- A 2-ship, not in range. - Get 'em there. Push 'em hard.
交火,給我一個PSS-SOF坐標.收到
Fires, get me a PSS-SOF grid. Roger that.
66號,這裡是阿爾法39
66, this is Three Niner Alpha.
裝甲車上路了,零點也啟動了空中支援
Convoy's en route and Zero's pushing fast air,
但是你們還得挺一會兒 - 66號,收到
but you're gonna have to hang in there.- 66, acknowledged, over.
我們發現了另外一個入口!
We gotta find another point of entrance!
RPG火箭!
RPG!
這裡有個缺口!
There's an opening!
謝謝,塔利班先生!
Thank you, Mister Taliban!
漢克,希基!
Hank, Hick!
安全!安全!
Clear! Clear!
- 安全! - 走著!
- Clear! - Let's go!
這裡安全!
It's all clear!
好吧,瑞恩,終於有地方了,死戰到底
Alright, Ryan, we got a compound, dead up there.
收到.走!
Roger that. Go!
前進!
Moving!
發現敵人!
Contact grid!
- 走! - 掩護!
- Moving! - Covering!
掩護!
Covering!
- 掩護! - 走!
- Covering! - Moving!
- 安全! - 安全!
- Clear! - Clear!
安全!
Clear!
- 安全! - 安全!
- Clear! - Clear!
手雷!
Grenade!
- 他們包圍我們了! - 阿爾法39
- They're surrounding us! - Three Niner Alpha.
報告戰況
Send sitrep. Over.
- 讓我們進去? - 我覺得他想幫我們
- Inviting us in? - I think he wants to help.
66號,阿爾法39.報告你們的情況
66. Three Niner Alpha. Sitrep, please.
66號,報告你們的情況
66, send sitrep. Over.
阿爾法39,66號
Three Niner Alpha, 66.
阿爾法39,發送
Three Niner Alpha, send.
66號,我們在一個地方進行防守...特拉維斯!
66, we're hold up inside compound at grid... Travis!
坐標是魁北克,4133...
Quebec, Quebec, 4133...
魁北克,4133-8921
Quebec, Quebec, 4133-8921.
我們被一群反政府武裝份子包圍了
We have a section plus of insurgents encircling compound.
我們4個人需要撤離地點,越快越好
We need QRF extraction for 4 PAX, ASA-fucking-P.
我們看見一個老人,古怪的眼睛盯著我們,他想...
We got an elder with crazy eyes, he's uh...
他邀請我們進屋.我們準備進去
he's asking us inside. I'm moving in.
我們要在這裡防守
We'll strong-point from here. Over.
- 他說古怪的眼睛? - 是的
- Did he say crazy eyes? - Yeah.
我能知道這個老人的細節嗎?
Can I get a description of the elder?
66號,這裡是零點
66, this is Zero.
描述一下對方.- 66號,你沒聽見嗎?
Describe the friendly. - 66, did you not hear me?
我們現在需要撤離地點!
We need QRF extraction now!
這很重要
It's important.
66號,我再說一次,描述一下對方
66, I say again, describe the friendly.Over.
66號,這個老人,嗯...
66, elder is about, uh...
我說不清,他是阿富汗人.古怪的眼睛,膚色很特殊
I don't know, he's Afghan old. Weird eyes, different colours.
等一下,零點,他們被圍困了
Break, break. Zero, they're jammed here,
我們要把他們救出來!
we gotta get them out!
阿爾法39.我們在努力
Three Niner Alpha, we're pushing. Will advise.
靠!
Fuck!
讓我們進去吧! 快點! 進去!
Let's move in! Come on! Let's move in!
- 安全! - 安全!
- Clear! - Clear!
每個人守住一個角落
Everybody take a quarter.
阿爾法39,66號在屋子裡觀察情況
Three Niner Alpha, 66 looking for status on that ride home.
66號,阿爾法39,接應部隊距離還有2英里
66, Three Niner Alpha, QRF is two zero Mikes out
你們離敵人武裝很近
and you are danger close for artillery.
你們必須守住.我們會盡快過去接你們
You'll have to hunker down. We'll get you out of there ASAP.
66號,收到.我們自力更生
66, roger, out. We're on our own.
- 他們暫時幫不上忙? - 很要堅持一會兒.好吧,夥計們,我們準備一下
- They can't get anything to us? - Not for a while. Okay, guys, let's arm up.
什麼情況?
What the fuck?
手雷,我需要手雷
Grenade. We need a grenade.
我有一個,給
I got one. Here.
你覺得他們在幹什麼?
What do you think they're doing?
和我們一樣唄,準備好
Same as us, getting ready.
看見什麼了嗎? 他們有82型迫擊炮
You see anything? They got an 82 recoilless!
哦,太好了
Oh, great.
- 大家沒事吧? - 沒事!
- Everybody okay? - Good!
- 我沒事 - 你呢?
- I'm good. - You?
- 他在幹什麼呢? - 我不知道
- What's he doing? - I don't know.
他們殺死了他!
They killed him!
- 夥計們,這是我們的權利 - 彼此彼此
- Gents, it's been a privilege. - Likewise.
幹掉所有到這裡的人!
Kill every fucker that comes through those doors!
收到
Roger that.
停止射擊!
Hold your fire!
塔利班? 沒有塔利班
Taliban? No Taliban.
我們安全了?
We're safe?
你相信他嗎?
You trust him?
準備行動!
Let's gear up!
走吧!
Let's go!
謝謝
Thank you.
- 安全! - 安全!
- Clear! - Clear!
安全!安全!
Clear!
安全!
他們都去哪了?
Where the hell'd they go?
阿爾法39,66號,我們在村子裡,已經安全
Three Niner Alpha, 66, we're clear in the village.
我們向集合撤離點進發,坐標4012-8883
Moving to rendezvous point at grid 4012-8883.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, acknowledged.
魁北克坐標4012-8883
RV Quebec Quebec 4012-8883. Over.
零點,這裡是阿爾法39.66號回來了
Zero, this is Three Niner Alpha. 66 coming home. Over.
零點,收到
Zero, acknowledged.
靠!
Fuck!
坎大哈空軍基地
KAF.
在阿富汗就好像在火星上一樣
You might as well be on Mars as in Afghanistan.
我們在沙漠的中部
We're out in the middle of the desert,
被各種武裝力量包圍
surrounded by a force of razor wire.
這些是多達45種民族組成的武裝力量
It's a coalition force from over 45 different nations.
這裡三分之二的士兵
Two thirds of the soldiers deployed here
甚至沒有看過這個國家
never even see the country.
他們只是看著該死的牆壁,防禦中心,提姆 霍斯頓
They just see blast walls, DFACs, Tim Hortons.
沒有人真正知道基地裡到底有多少人
Nobody even knows how many people are on this base.
三萬五,四萬五還是六萬?
35, 45, 60,000?
就是這裡.在情報中心
It's here, inside the wire,
我們組織一切事物,傳達到外面
that we organize everything that goes on outside the wire.
一半的時間,我們得到的是錯誤的信息
Half the time, we got it wrong,
但這也意味著,我們得到了一半正確的信息
but that means half the time, we got it right.
這裡的消耗相當龐大
It's a vast organism that consumes
每天需要14噸食物,並且還要往湖裡排泄垃圾
14 metric tons of food a day and shits into a lake
讓人感覺空氣中有30%排泄物的氣味
that fills the air with 30% fecal matter.
在坎大哈空軍基地,你甚至能聞到你自己糞便的味道
In KAF, you breathe your own shit.
先生們,我建造了一條路
I'm building a road, gentlemen.
我建造的路就像匕首一樣
I'm building a big fucking road and it's going like a dagger
將插進敵人的心臟,把他幹掉
into the heart of the enemy and it is fucking him up.
每天早上他醒來,我就站在那裡
Every morning he wakes up, I'm standing there
打他的臉
and I'm punching him in his fucking face.
現在,我們距離本傑瓦爾的洪恩已經非常近了
Now, we've never been this deep into the Horn of Panjwai,
但是鬣狗大路就在那裡,她也在那裡等待著
but Hyena Road is in there and she's in there to stay.
但是他們不喜歡,因為我們限制了
And they don't like it, 'cause we're fucking
他們的活動自由. 所以他們干擾我們的
with their freedom of movement. So they're going after
運輸卡車,軍車還有工人
our dump trucks and our gravel trucks and our workers.
你說的是什麼?
What are you saying?
我是說,我們自過去四個月裡已經失去了36名平民
I'm saying I've lost 36 civilians in the last 4 months
這個混蛋必須停止行動
and this bullshit has got to stop.
我需要你的幫助
And I'm gonna need a little help from you.
- 將軍,我就是一個普通人 - 你是巴什 達烏德 可汗,BDK
- General, I am just one man. - You're Bashir Daoud Khan, BDK.
你有民兵組織
You're one man with a militia.
我是你們的夥伴
And I am your partner in peace.
所以我需要你的耳目,需要你還有你的兒子
So I need your eyes and ears and I need you and your son
能參加我們的慶典
to be at our little dedication ceremony,
那裡有多少輛車,肖迪?
how many clicks, there, Shorty?
- 15輛,長官 - 15輛車
- 15, sir. - 15 clicks of hardtop
準備去洪恩
into the Horn.
你的出席將...意義重大
Your presence there would be... very meaningful.
鬣狗大路是給阿富汗的禮物
Hyena Road is a gift to all Afghans.
能參加慶典是我父親和我
It would be an honour for my father and I
最大的榮幸
to attend your ceremony.
太好了
Out-fucking-standing.
- 謝謝,將軍 - 謝謝你,長官
- Thank you, general. - Thank you, sir.
瞧那個小傻瓜,他很像是卡利古拉
Look at the little prick. He's like Caligula.
建造鬣狗大路會容易很多的
It'd be a fuck of a lot easier to get Hyena built
如果那個小傻瓜不在竊竊私語的話
if that prick would stop breathing.
正確,你是對的.我要坐飛機
Right there, you're right. I'm gonna hop a flight.
我要去斯波,去見一位長者
I wanna get to Sper, run down a lead on an elder.
告訴阿姆斯特朗,準備飛機
Tell Armstrong I'll call in from the FOB.
你不想和我在一起了?
You don't want to hang out with me?
哦,你知道的,我很想的
Oh, you know there is nothing I'd rather do
但是西部文明的未來
but the future of Western civilization
還要取決於我去斯波打拼
depends on my ass getting out to Sper.
亞歷山大在2500年前
Alexander the Great marched into this graveyard
攻入了這片土地
about 2,500 years ago.
他說,進攻容易,防守難
Easy to march in, hard to march out. His words.
他總和他的母親相互寫信
He and his mother wrote to each other all the time.
一天,他收到了一封來自他母親的信
One day, he got a letter from her saying,
"這到底怎麼回事? 你能用一天半的時間征服世界上很多著名的地方
"What the hell? You conquered most of the known world in a day and a half,
怎麼卻在阿富汗停滯不前?"
what are you doing bogged down in Afghanistan?"
她抓起個袋子,往裡面裝滿了泥土
He grabbed a bag and shoveled it full of dirt
他把這袋泥土和一條消息一起送回了希臘他母親那裡
and had it sent back to Greece with a message to his mother,
"拿這些泥土倒在皇宮周圍
"Take this dirt and dump it around the palace,
看看會發生什麼"
see what happens."
6-1,遭受攻擊,左側,10點鐘方向
6-1, taking fire, left, 10 o'clock.
300米,右路受阻
300 metres, breaking right.
消滅敵人
Clear to engage.
目標被摧毀,收到
Target is neutralized. Roger.
後來亞歷山大的母親
So Alexander's mother
把泥土倒在了皇宮的周圍
spread the dirt all around the palace.
夜裡,一些隨從出來了
Later that night, a couple of attendants showed up
來確認她沒事
to make sure she was alright.
一個說,"你走前面,我跟著你"
One says, "Go ahead, after you."
另一個說,"不,我跟著你"
And the other says, "No, after you."
然後第一個人又說,"不,我堅持"
And the first one says, "No, I insist."
第二個人又說,"別告訴我該怎麼做"
And the second one says, "Don't you tell me what to do."
他們拿著劍互相攻擊
They pull their swords and go at it
直到他們互相殺死對方
till they kill each other.
亞歷山大的母親看到了這一切
Alexander's mother watched all this
給他回了一封信說,"好的,現在我明白了'"
and wrote a note to him saying, "Okay, okay, now I get it."
他回信說:"就連泥土都可能是敵人"
And he wrote back saying, "Even the dirt is hostile."
在阿富汗,狗咬狗
In Afghanistan, dogs fight dogs,
鳥吃鳥,人殺人
birds fight birds, men kill men.
開火!
Fire!
哦,夥計,快點,給我看看照片
Oh, man, come on, show me their picture.
- 介意我坐這裡嗎? - 不介意,批准了,請吧
- Mind if I join you? - Not at all, Warrant. Please.
嘿,我剛剛從工程師那裡得到了新的消息
Hey, I got an update from the engineer
昨天在鬣狗大路上
on that stretch of Hyena from yesterday.
他們清理了8顆地雷
They cleared 8 IEDs in all.
最後一次出錯了
Something went wrong with the last one.
一個傢伙失去了半條腿.他們把他送回國了
The guy lost his leg above the knee. They airlifted him to Landstuhl.
我覺得我們需要談談,嘿,嗯...
I think we need to talk. Hey, uh...
嘿,簡.抱歉打擾你們
Hi, Jen. Sorry to interrupt here.
瑞恩,我是皮特 米歇爾
Ryan, I'm Pete Mitchell,
旅裡的執行長官
one of the effects guys with Brigade.
我不想打攪你吃飯,但是你介意
I don't mean to wreck your meal, but you mind
我有些話要和你說嗎? - 好的
if I have a word with you? - Sure.
一會兒見
Catch up to you later.
當你和你的夥計們在哈吉 巴巴作戰時
I was in the TOC where you guys
我正在指揮中心
had that engagement in Haji Baba.
你們很幸運
You were fucking lucky.
你到這裡來就是和我講這些?
You come all the way out here to tell me that?
不是的
Nope.
不,我來這裡是因為
No, I came out here because.and I could be
有些事不合適...- 你知道的,坦白講
way out of line here but... - you know, manifestly,
你和 簡 有點什麼事
you and Jen got a little something going.
作為一個戰鬥團隊
On behalf of the entire battle group,
我要表達我們大家的妒忌之心!
I'd just like to express our collective fucking jealousy!
你有女人嗎?
You got a girl?
是的,女人是我回家的夢想
Yeah. Woman of my dreams, back home.
- 她知道你做什麼嗎? - 我妻子? 不
- Does she know what you do? - My wife? No
她以為我在情報中心
She thinks I work inside the wire
我只能這樣,讓她能睡個安穩覺
and I'm gonna leave it that way. Let her sleep easy at night.
告訴我
Tell me something.
你對普什圖法典知道多少?
How much you do you know about Pashtunwali?
不管手冊裡怎麼講,你知道
Whatever's in the handbook, you know
它是一種部族編碼,很古老,哦,是的
It's a tribal code. It's old. Oh yeah.
它太古老了,看起來像是伊斯蘭教的某種附加語
It's so old they look upon Islam as a kind of recent add-on.
- 這是什麼? - 是海棗
- What are those? - They're dates.
當地的. 通便的
They're local. They help you shit.
這些代碼由一些,嗯...
The code has got a bunch of, uh...
他們稱之為核心
Well, they call them pillars.
其中一種是潘納
And one of them is Panah,
意思就是...保護,所以當那位長者
which means... protection, more or less. So when that elder
邀請你進屋時,等於給了你一個潘納
invited you into his home, he gave you Panah:
對你沒有惡意
no harm could come to you.
嗯...你的意思是那麼我欠他一個人情?
Uh... so I owe him, you mean?
他是為真主而做的,不是為了你
Well, he did it for Allah, didn't do it for you.
但是你還活著,這很重要
But you're still breathing, so that'd be your call.
那位長者...
This elder...
他會講英語嗎?
He speak any English?
不會,只是簡單幾個詞語而已
No. Just a couple words.
他有什麼特點嗎,傷疤?
Any marks about him, any scars?
- 沒有,但是他的眼睛很古怪. - 怎麼古怪了?
- No, but he had weird eyes. - Weird how?
他的左眼是棕色的,右眼卻是深藍色的
His left eye was brown and his right eye was deep blue.
嗯
Hmm.
那麼這傢伙是誰? 你為什麼...
So who is this guy? Why do you...
為什麼給我這個潘納
Why did he give me this Panah?
這也是我想知道的
That's what I wanna know.
明天早上我帶一個巡邏隊回到村子裡去
I got a patrol going back into the village in the morning.
我希望你也能來
I'd really like if you'd come along with me,
見識一下那個傢伙
help me ID the guy.
- 好的,沒問題,我會來的 - 0900
- Yeah, sure, I'll be there. - 0900.
- 好的 - 好的
- Alright. - Alright.
- 明早見 - 好的
- I'll see you in the morning. - Yeah.
- 你怎麼想? - 嗯...
- What are you thinking? - Hmm...
我在想我們在塞浦路斯的酒店房間
I'm thinking about our hotel room in Cyprus.
嗯...
Um...
好吧,我想說點事情
Okay, I'm gonna say something,
我要對我們兩個說,很糟糕
and I say it for both of us and it's going to be shitty.
必須要說
It's gotta be said.
- 靠 - 你知道我是
- Fuck me. - You know that I am
很喜歡你的,還有塞浦路斯...
completely crazy about you, and Cyprus was...
塞浦路斯非常不錯
Cyprus was perfect.
我們也是完美的一對兒
We're perfect.
但是,我們不能再這樣繼續下去了,我們都知道的
But we can't keep doing this, we both know that.
如果我們繼續的話,我們都會被開除的
If we get caught, I'm gonna get cashiered.
這是我的事業.也是我的事業
This is my career. It's mine too.
我知道,這就是我要說的
I know, this is what I'm saying.
當我們...還要輪流回家,我們就會明白了
When we... rotate home, we'll see.
但是現在,我們在這裡,必須停下來
But right now, while we're here, it's got to stop.
那麼這就是分手了?
So this is it?
就算是吧
I think it has to be.
這簡直是世界末日啊
This is like fucking Armageddon.
我知道
I know.
你知道,這裡沒有什麼
You know there's nothing that I would rather do right now
比我認識你做的更正確的事情了
than climb over there and fraternize the shit out of you.
嗯...
Hmm...
你不能憑一句話就結束了
You can't dump me in one sentence
然後說些亂七八糟的
then say something like that in the next.
啊...!
Ah...!
現在,我們要進入葡萄地,如果你看見電線
Now, when we get to the grape fields, if you see wire,
金屬或是塑料之類的
you see metal, you see plastic,
趕快轉身,別踩上去
newly turned dirt, don't step on 'em.
你不小心踩上了.別亂動
You didn't drop it, don't pick it up.
請和巡邏隊的士兵保持
Try to stay at least five body lengths
至少五個身體的距離
between the next man in the patrol.
當我們進入村子的時候
When we get in the village,
你如果看見包裹著衣服的女人
you're gonna see women dressed in bags.
請不要盯著她們看
Please don't stare at them.
我知道也許你在多倫多活著巴黎也見過類似的人群
I know you've probably seen that in Toronto or Paris,
但是你沒有在這裡見過
but you haven't seen it here.
這裡的女人對你可能很有吸引力
Here, those bags are like magnets for your eyes.
如果你總盯著她們看,她們會對我們不利的
If you get caught staring at them, it'll fuck shit up for us.
快速止血器,止血帶,繃帶
Quick clot, tourniquet, bandage.
我都不知道怎麼使用啊
I don't know how to use any of that.
夫人,如果是你需要使用的話,也不需要你親自來用
Ma'am, if it has to be used, it won't be you using it.
嘿!眼神!
Hey! Eyes!
在戰爭中,能見到
In my job, it is a great honour
像您這樣一位長者是我的榮幸
to meet elders such as yourself.
今天,我見到了您.所以今天是個好日子
Today, I meet you, so it's a good day.
但是,我希望能見到村裡的另一位長者
But I was hoping to meet another elder in this village.
她說,"我是這裡唯一的長者,沒有其他人了"
He says that, "I'm the only elder, and there is no other."
奇怪了.有人告訴我,這裡還有一位很重要的人物
Strange. Someone told me there was another important man
他就住在村子裡,但是不管他叫什麼
that lived in this village, but I forget his name.
這個人令人難以忘懷
But this person said you couldn't forget him
因為他的兩隻眼睛顏色不一樣
because he had two different coloured eyes.
嘿,嘿,嘿!你怎麼回事?
Hey, hey, hey! What's in your head?
你站太高了
You're too high.
你都能看見沒穿衣服的女人了
You can see the women without their bags.
下來!下來! 抱歉,長官
Get down! Get down! Sorry, sir.
我認為你知道我的意思
I think you know who I mean.
他說他是個幽靈
He says he's a ghost.
即使是幽靈也需要住在什麼地方啊
Even ghosts have to live somewhere.
他說,他們大多住在坎大哈
He says most of them live in Kandahar City.
哈吉,你在幹什麼?
Haji, what the fuck are you doing?
地毯髒了!
The carpets, they are dusty!
整個國家都髒了
The entire country is dusty.
快點,喝茶去,到我辦公室來
Come on, let's have some tea. Step into my office.
你好嗎,皮特? 你的家人好嗎?
How are you doing, Pete? How's your family?
過得如何? 不錯
How's your time? It's good.
你怎樣?
And how's yours?
我從喀布爾聽說? 你什麼時候能見到他們?
You heard from Kabul? When will you see 'em?
很快
Soon.
你皺眉頭
You're frowning.
我覺得你太瘋狂了
I thought you were crazy,
但是我錯了.我並不想出錯
but I was wrong, and I don't like to be wrong.
我外甥說也許他在這裡
My cousin says maybe he is here.
- 在坎大哈?  - 他認為是的
- In K-City? - He thinks so.
他為什麼回來了?
Why is he back?
- 如果是他 - 但是眼睛不對!
- If it's even him. - But the eyes!
如果是他,你覺得你能帶我去見他嗎?
If it is him, do you think you can get me to see him?
我舅舅明天會安排的
My uncle has arranged it for tomorrow.
告訴他,我準備帶一個人單獨去
Tell them I'm gonna bring along another guy,
狙擊手在戰鬥群裡
the master sniper with the battle group.
還有一件事.不大相關的
One other thing. It's not relational.
- 有關的 - 有關的,是的
- Related. - Related, yes.
我聽到一些關於襲擊的事情
I'm hearing something about an attack.
- 在坎大哈? - 很快
- In K-City? - Soon.
我就知道這麼多.我發現更多信息
That's all I know. As soon as I
我會告訴你的
find out more, I will tell you.
好的
Okay.
你怎麼樣? 有什麼需要的嗎?
How are you? Do you need anything?
不,我很好
No, I'm good.
你總是說你很好
You always say you're good.
我是阿富汗人!
I'm Afghan!
哦.聽著,我給你帶來了...
Oh, listen, I got you...
一些洗髮水
I got you some of that shampoo,
護手霜,你們很喜歡的東西
some of that... hand cream you guys are so crazy about.
- 謝謝.太好了 - 別客氣,朋友
- Thank you. This is great. - You're welcome, my friend.
這是我的最愛
It's my favourite.
夥計們!聽著,這次是直接行動
Guys, listen up, this is straight from the brass.
夥計們!聽著!好的
Guys! Listen! Alright.
別搞砸了.你們這幫笨蛋!
No more fraternizing with goats, you bunch of goat fuckers!
好的,聽好
Okay, listen up.
今晚4名隊員出發
All four DETs are out tonight,
所有隊員要注意觀察和匯報,除了你,特拉維斯
all ops are observe and report, except for you, Travis.
你的人在鬣狗大路上
You guys are on that bend in Hyena
樹傍邊,所以注意警惕
where that fucking tree is, so keep your eyes peeled.
我要臨時退居二線一天
I've been seconded to intel for the day,
我去坎大哈
so I'm heading into K-City.
沃爾夫這裡你負責
Wilf here is going to step up.
好的,我得到了一些壞消息
Alright. I got some bad news.
他們抓走了
They grabbed a couple of guys
第10山地連的幾個兄弟
from 10th Mountain Dog Company.
- 什麼? - 是的
- What? - Yeah.
我也不知道詳情,但是他們可能是排雷小隊的
I don't know the details, but there was an IED of some sort
還有兩個在特立斯被抓走的
and the Talis grabbed two of them.
他們還活著嗎?
Are they alive?
是的
Yeah.
靠!
Fuck!
你可以用炸彈轟了我
You can blow me up with an IED...
用AK機槍向我掃射,用裝甲車幹掉我!
shoot me with an AK, fucking run me over with a LAV!
我...我沒事
I'm... I'm fucking fine with that.
但是,別讓我在中東
But do not let me get taken alive by these...
這些傢伙面前苟且偷生
fucking medievalists.
你沒事吧?
You good?
他們到底和你說了什麼?
What exactly do they do to you?
- 機密 - 新的命令!
- It's unspeakable. - New comm logs!
填表格. 他們是什麼意思?
Fill them out. What do you mean?
嘿...機密的意思就是不能說
Hey... Unspeakable means we don't fucking speak about it.
目標倒下,撤退
Targets down. Let's back up.
第一次啊,感覺如何?
First time, well... how do you feel?
很好
Good.
- 準備好了嗎? - 不,還沒
- Ready to go? - No, not quite.
我要拉臭.什麼?! 為什麼?
I gotta take a shit. What?! Why?
為什麼? 我不知道.也許因為...
Why? I don't know. Maybe because my...
腸子裡都是屎? 給我個袋子
long intestine's full of shit? Give me the bag.
謝謝
Thanks.
多美好的夜晚啊
What a beautiful night.
你知道,如果他們能把這個地方拿下的話,我就回去
You know, if they get this place together, I'd come back.
帶喬伊去野營. 野營?
Bring Joey camping. Camping?
- 是的 - 在坎大哈?
- Yeah. - In Kandahar?
為什麼不行?
Why the fuck not?
2號目標解決了.準備回家
Number 2's fully offloaded. Good to go.
阿爾法39
Three Niner Alpha.
這裡是66號,準備去撤離點
This is 66 Bravo ready for extraction. Over.
走吧,沃爾夫
Let's go, Wilf.
- 多美麗的早晨啊 - 是啊,只有兩個小時
- It's a beautiful morning. - Yeah, it's been for two hours.
護衛隊什麼時候來?
How long until the convoy?
應該在路上了,也許還有5到10英里
Should be on the move, five to ten Mikes maybe.
他們是阿富汗人,你相信他們嗎?
These A&A dudes, you trust these guys?
用我生命保證
With my life.
這是他們的戰爭,我們只是路過
It's their war. We're just along for the ride.
嘿,沃爾德
Hey, Walid.
嗯?
Huh?
收音機裡是什麼?
What's he got going on the tunes?
利夫 加勒特
Leif Garrett.
- 開玩笑吧 - 是他
- You're shitting me. - Yeah.
放大點聲音,大家都聽聽!
Come on, put it out, for all to hear!
好的,護衛隊來了,安靜!
Okay, convoy's on the move. Mount up!
威士忌高爾夫9號,我們進來了
Golf Niner Whisky, we're pulling in. Over.
收到.威士忌高爾夫9號.進來吧
Roger that, Golf Niner Whisky. Join in.
右轉
Take this right.
這裡是威士忌高爾夫9號,我們分開走
This is Golf Niner Whisky. We're breaking off.
感謝你帶路
Thanks for the tow.
皮特,這裡的某個地方
Pete, anywhere here.
- 這傢伙是誰? - 他被稱為清潔工
- Who is that guy? - He's called the Cleaner.
他是我見過的很勇敢的傢伙,最好的盟友
He's the bravest man I've ever known and my greatest ally.
他為我們工作,但是不能暴露身份
He works for us but can't be seen with us,
你是否知道我的意思.他的家在喀布爾
if you know what I mean. His family's up in Kabul
他在過去三年裡他都沒怎麼見過他的家人
and he hasn't seen them or slept in the same bed
和家人一起睡覺不超過3個晚上
for more than three nights running in the last two years.
他為什麼做這些?
Why's he doing it?
愛國? 我也不知道
Love of country? I honestly don't know.
不僅僅是為了我們付給他的錢
Can't just be for the money we pay him.
他說他叫穆罕默德
He says his name is Mohammed.
是啊,當然是的.麵包看起來不錯啊
Yeah, of course it is. This bread looks very good.
這是瑞恩,我們是朋友
My friend Ryan, we've been friends,
我們認識,並且相互友愛
we've known each other and loved each other
很多很多年
for many, many years.
你在哈吉 巴巴幫助了我的朋友
And you helped my friend in the village of Haji Baba.
我要為此報答你
And I would like to repay you for that kindness.
你一定需要些什麼
You must need something,
也許是清真寺裡的祈禱用的地毯
perhaps new prayer rugs for your mosque.
我要幫助你
I would like to help with that.
- 這是多少錢啊? - 我也不知道
- How much is that? - I have no idea.
給你的村子
This is for your village.
他說,"不知道原因就接受禮物
He says, "Only a fool accepts a gift
是很愚昧的"
without knowing what it's for."
有一個傳說中的戰士
There is a legendary warrior,
一個穆斯林人在吉哈德和蘇聯人作戰
a mujahideen in the Jihad against the Soviets.
他被稱為沙漠之獅
He was called the Lion of the Desert.
他說,"他聽說過這個人"
He says, "he's heard of this man."
我的意思是他回來了,再次參加聖戰
The word is that he's back. He's once again mujahid.
你聽說過這個傳言嗎?
Have you heard anything about these rumours?
我可以問問你們從哪裡來嗎?
May I ask where you're from?
他說."他的村子是阿布杜拉 喬"
He says his village is called Abdullah Jan.
啊,所以你是巴基斯坦人
Ah. So you're Pakistani.
我在巴基斯坦待了很多年
I have been Pakistani for many years,
穆斯林1400人,普什圖族5000人
a Muslim for 1,400 and a Pashtun for 5,000.
我明白了
I understand.
如果你聽到任何關於沙漠之獅的消息...
If you hear anything about the Lion...
我會很感激的
I would greatly appreciate it.
那麼他是巴基斯坦人?
So he's Pakistani?
不
No.
不,那只是個測試
No, that was just a kind of test.
阿布杜拉 喬只是個被毀了的村子
Abdullah Jan is just the ruins of some village
橫穿斯濱 波大格的邊界
across the border from Spin Boldak.
那裡已經有上百年
Nobody's really lived there
沒有人居住了.尤其是他們
for a couple hundred years, least of all him.
那麼他不是從村子裡來的人
So he's not just some guy from a village.
不,他不是
No, he's not.
他是沙漠之獅.人們就是這樣稱呼他的
He's the Lion of the Desert. That's what his people call him.
但是俄羅斯人稱他為幽靈
But the Russians, they called him the Ghost
因為他們無法殺死他
'cause they couldn't kill him.
他們射殺了他4次,炸了他2次
They shot him four times, they blew him up twice.
每次,他都能逃到山那邊的
And each time, his guys would get him up over the mountains
巴基斯坦的紅十字會裡去
and into the Red Cross tents in Pakistan.
他們想讓他妥協
And they'd get him stitched up
他卻每次都把俄羅斯人炸飛
and he'd be back out there blowing Russians out of the sky.
我們剛才會見了一個大人物
We just met a very big gun,
就像隆美爾或者是帕頓
like a Rommel or a Patton.
這傢伙還是個孩子的時候就和蘇聯紅軍打過仗
This guy beat the Red Army and he was a kid when he did it.
當蘇聯撤出後,他和塔利班達成了協議
When the Russians pulled out, he cut a deal with the Talibans,
"我要回到我的葡萄地去,我不希望
"I'm going back to my grape fields, I don't want any part
這裡再發生任何內戰.別來打攪我"
of your stupid civil war. Just leave me alone."
他所做的,有些不可思議
Which they did, which was kind of weird,
因為一般說來
'cause generally speaking,
塔利班不會放過反對他們的人
the Talis went after anybody who stood against them.
但是對於他,由於某些原因,他們卻很牽就他
But him, for some reason, they just left him alone.
- 但是他回來了 - 他回來了
- But now he's back. - He's back,
我在想是什麼原因.像他這樣一個人
and I gotta figure out why. A guy like him,
以他的勢力,沒可能啊
with his influence, he could prob
我們遭到炸彈襲擊,汽車炸彈還有其他的
We got multiple bombers, vehicle-borne and coordinated.
報告平民傷亡情況
Reporting civilian casualties,
有幾個平民陣亡,在城市中心地帶...
multiple civ KIA, city centre...
派無人機去坎大哈
Got a VBIED southwest Kandahar City.
有幾個平民受傷
Multiple casualties.
A&A 報告,受到襲擊,線路1,阿爾法7-5
A&A reports taking fire, I-route 1 and Alpha 7-5.
一定炸到發動機了
Must have hit the engine block.
- 見鬼 - 皮特,護衛隊呢?
- Goddamnit. - Peter, where's the convoy?
- 我們和護衛隊失去了聯絡 - 好吧...
- We lost the convoy. - Alright...
零點,威士忌高爾夫9號,嗯...
Zero, Golf Niner Whisky, uh...
我們遇到敵人.零點.收到
I have contact. Over. Zero, acknowledged.
是的,威士忌高爾夫9號,我們遇到敵人
Yeah, Golf Niner Whisky, we have contact
在魁北克坐標232-129.我軍無傷亡
at grid Quebec Romeo 232-129. We have no mil casualties.
我要走路過去了
I have mobility kill. Over.
零點,收到. 有報告說
Zero, roger. Be advised we have reports
在警署周圍有很多
of multiple SBVIED in vicinity
恐怖份子. 更多信息一會兒跟進
of police headquarters. More to follow.
- 威士忌高爾夫9號,收到 - 是的,很像是
- Golf Niner Whisky, send. - Yeah, it looks like
是塔利班干的. 趕快撤離那裡
the Talis are at it again. It's a shit storm out there.
我建議你迅速撤出城市
I advise you try and exit city,
去納森 史密斯營地,就是這個
move to Camp Nathan Smith, ride this one out.
威士忌高爾夫9號,收到
Golf Niner Whisky. Wilco. Out.
還會有爆炸的! 快走!
There's another explosion! Let's go!
我們必須離開這裡,往北走
We're gonna have to move. Heading north.
見鬼,不能帶著無線電嗎
Goddamnit, can't get the radio.
別弄無線電了,用我的無線電
Forget the radio, we'll use my MBITR.
我們走吧! 快走!
Let's go! We gotta move!
- 我要把它炸掉. - 沃爾德?
- I'm gonna have to blow it. - Walid?
- 是的 - 過來! 到車後去
- Yeah. - Come! Behind the car.
手雷!
Frag out!
米歇爾, 帶上沃爾德.去那邊的角落
Mitchell, grab Walid. Punch up to that corner.
掩護. 收到,跟我走
Cover my 6. Roger. Stay with me
安全
Clear.
傻B
Dick.
走吧
Let's go.
他們上屋頂了
They're moving on the fucking rooftops.
安全,走著
Clear, let's go.
RPG火箭!
RPG!
你沒事吧?
You good?
是的,還好
Yeah, good.
- 你能開槍嗎? - 我? 不行,我是頭兒
- Can you shoot? - Me? Fuck no, I'm intel.
零點,威士忌高爾夫9號 我確認這裡有很多恐怖份子
Zero, Golf Niner Whisky. I have PID on multiple hostiles,
剛才地點40米以東.發生交火
40 metres east of last position. Engaging. Wait out.
零點,收到
Zero, roger.
- 前進! - 掩護
- Moving! - Covering.
塔利班一點鐘方向!
Tali at one o'clock!
- 啊!- 目的倒地!
- Ah! - Target down!
米歇爾,跟上我!
Mitchell, come up to me!
走啊,快走!
Move it, go, go, go!
等一下
Hold up.
我需要你去左翼
I need you to punch left,
走那邊的小巷,我掩護你
down that alleyway. I'll cover you.
你行嗎? 是的,我可以
You good? Yeah, good to go.
預備
Standby.
走!
Go!
安全
Clear.
太糟了
This is bad.
遇上勁敵了
You piss with the dick you got.
前進
Moving.
- 換子彈,掩護我 - 好的
- Changing mags, cover me. - Alright.
前進
Moving.
屋頂,9點鐘方向
Rooftop, 9 o'clock!
安全
Clear.
- 開槍啊 - 我不殺孩子
- Shoot him. - I don't shoot kids.
安全 安全
Clear. Clear.
炸彈! 啊!
Bomber! Ah!
是自己人,是清潔工!
It's my guy, it's my guy, it's the Cleaner!
快走!
Go, go, go, go!
哈吉,你哪兒弄來的卡車?
Haji, where did you get this truck?
我舅舅的!
My uncle!
當然!
Of course!
我在閒逛,你不一直瞭解這個城市!
I hung around, you never know in this city!
我聽到了槍聲,就過來照看一下你們! 我們太幸運了!
I heard the gunfire, came looking for you! We got lucky!
靠,是的!
Fuck, yeah!
零點,這裡是威士忌高爾夫9號,我們撤離了
Zero, this is Golf Niner Whisky, we're heading out.
零點,收到
Zero, acknowledged.
見鬼!
Goddamn!
太痛快了,橫衝直撞,太瘋狂了!
That was balls out, flat out, fucking insanity!
5枚自殺式炸彈,一大箱RPG火箭
Five suicide bombers, a rack of RPGs,
死17人,傷37人.我要喝杯咖啡
17 dead and 37 wounded. I gotta get a coffee.
我們知道他們之後要幹什麼嗎?
Do we know what they were after?
是的,警察總署.我們差點陷進去
Yeah. Police headquarters. We just got caught up in it.
那是坎大哈 卡瑪.夥計,就是那裡
That is Kandahar karma, baby, that's what that is.
但是我不得不說,你使用槍械
But I gotta say, you handle your rifle
動作很僵硬啊
like you got ice in your veins.
那些塔利班人使用AK步槍
Well, those Talis were using AKs,
很不錯的武器,如果你在電話亭裡
which is great weapons if you're in a phone booth.
你在這個城市干很久了? 是的
You work the city a lot? A fair bit, yeah.
- 不可思議的工作 - 哦,是的...
- You got a weird job. - Oh, yeah...
那你呢...你不是嗎?
And you... and you don't?
我? 不!
Me? No!
不,所有人都知道規矩.你拿起一把AK步槍,一個PRG火箭筒
No, everybody knows the rules. You pick up an AK, an RPG,
你應該聽說過.這裡沒有灰色地帶
you're gonna hear about it. There's no gray area.
那麼,除非回家,他們會認為你做的事情
Well, except back home, where they think what you do
有一點...我不知道...事先計劃好的
is a little too... I don't know... premeditated.
但是我的話? 內心和想法? 他們會欣然接受
But my shit? Hearts and Minds? They lap that stuff up
因為這是道德上的問題
'cause it's got a moral ring to it,
儘管他們多半只是PR
even if it's mostly just PR.
你相信這些?
You believe that?
這裡的人...
These people here...
他們對不起我給他們提供的幫助
they got no use for what we have on offer.
他們不需要賈斯丁?比伯和托馬斯·傑斐遜
They don't want Justin Bieber and Tom Jefferson
或者是什麼破色情雜誌
and our fucking pornography.
他們只需要錢和安逸的環境
They just want our money and a little bit of stability.
- 那我們如何能贏? - 這裡沒有輸贏
- So how do we win? - There is no winning
這裡只會有停戰協定和
There's just an end state and that's gonna get laid down
外交政策,不取決於我們
by foreign policy, not by us.
你是個玩世不恭的人
You're a cynical man.
不是關於這個國家,我不是的
Not about this country, I'm not.
不是關於這裡的人
Not about these people.
我也是.我只相信
Me neither. And I gotta believe
6美元一個彈夾的子彈
that if I put a $6 round,
打到了正確的地方
just one bullet in the right place,
我能改變一切
I could change everything.
你也許是對的
You may be right.
- 你要去斯波? - 不
- You gonna stick around Sper? - No.
我要搭飛機.我該出發了
I'm gonna hop a flight. Should grab my gear.
我會聯繫你.我就在附近
I'll be in touch. I'll be around.
別說話,聽著
Don't say anything, just listen.
我知道這裡的形勢,我知道這不可能
I know our situation, I know it doesn't make sense,
但是你需要聽好
but you need to hear this from me.
我愛你
I love you.
從現在直到死
Right down to the bone, right down to the goddamned
你需要知道這些
fucking marrow. You need to know that.
好的.知道了
Ditto. All of it.
- 哈吉,你在幹什麼? - 洗洗椅子
- Haji, what are you doing? - Cleaning the chairs.
- 那不是你的工作 - 那是誰的工作呢?
- It's not your job. - Whose job is it?
管他呢
Well, it's nobody's.
這就是為什麼你的椅子總是很髒
This is why you have dirty chairs!
我要喝點茶,快點
I need some tea. Come on.
他都沒什麼可說的
Why would he even agree to a meeting
為什麼還要開會?
if he has absolutely nothing to say?
他也許想讓大家知道他回來了
Maybe he just wants the Coalition to know he's back.
也許吧,但是為什麼呢?
Maybe, but for what?
我們需要知道誰在村子裡
We need to know who's in that village.
你能去塔吉克地區
Can you get into the Tazkera Registry,
看看誰住在那裡?
find out who lives there?
我有個舅舅,他在政府工作
I have an uncle, he works in the Governor's palace.
天那,你到底有多少個舅舅?
God, how many uncles do you have?
很多
Pff. Many.
告訴我...
Tell me...
你覺得我的頭髮如何? 我用了洗髮水
What do you think of my hair? I've been using the shampoo.
看起來很順滑很有型
It looks silky smooth and very manageable.
- 啊! 我的手呢? - 嗯...
- Ah! And my hands? - Hmm...
柔軟,像個嬰兒
Soft, like a baby's bum.
你是最棒的
You're the best.
嘿,傑瑞,我需要幫助
Hey there, Chewey, I need a favour.
我在找地圖上標記的這個村子
I'm looking at a village at this grid marker.
那裡最近有的任何活動. 我不知道
Any events in the last, I don't know,
我是說最近六個月的? 好吧,皮特
say the last six months? Come on, Pete
- 我知道這個要通過阿姆斯特朗,但是我不知道自己尋找的是什麼
- I know I should go through Armstrong, but I don't know what I'm looking for.
我不能憑感覺做事情
I don't feel like doing a whole work up just on a hunch.
- 我想你想要一些可視化的東西 - 是的,任何能看見的
- You want a visual, I assume. - Anything with eyes, yeah.
我會告訴你的
I'll let you know.
謝謝
Thank you.
有用嗎?
Anything useful?
也許
Maybe.
我欠你什麼? 我要你
What do I owe you? I'll take your beer allotment
一個月的啤酒. 我也只有兩箱,和你一樣
at the end of the month. I only get two, same as you.
- 那我就都拿走 - 好吧,歸你了
- And I'll take them both. - Alright, they're yours.
你能把這些都搞清楚嗎? 謝謝,傑瑞
And you can clear all this shit off. Thanks, Chewey.
哦,是的.嗯...這幾天裡
Oh yeah, and, uh... one of these days,
我要策劃一次行動
I'm gonna split up a fire mission,
扭轉局面
turn my chair on the backside.
好的...
Okay...
嘿,哈吉,有什麼新消息嗎?
Hey, Haji, what do you got for me?
哦.很糟.是貝希爾
Oh, it's bad. It's Bashir's.
你開玩笑吧. 那不是巴什 達烏德 可汗的地盤嗎?
You're kidding me. BDK owns that land?
你確定? 記錄上是這樣顯示的
You're sure? It's in the record.
好吧,聽著,你明天能去斯波嗎?
Alright, listen, can you get out to Sper tomorrow?
- 可以,沒問題 - 當你到大門的時候,如果有人問起
- Yes, no problem. - When you're at the gate, if anyone asks,
你就說你是承包商,你在學校工作
you're just a contractor, you're working on a school,
或者...我不知道,工廠或是其他什麼
or... I don't know, a fucking kite factory or something.
好的
Okay.
小心點,朋友
Take care, my friend.
你有乳腺增生
Have you had any tenderness in your breasts,
噁心或者只是濕疹嗎? 有點濕疹
or nausea or just the spotting? No, just the spotting.
我一直控制的不錯啊
I'm really managing my cycle.
我有六個月沒來月經了,但是...
I haven't had my period in six months, but...
我也不知道,也許我忘了吃避孕藥,或者...
I don't know, maybe I missed a pill or...
也許我有點偏執了!
maybe I'm just being paranoid!
不...
No...
如果我們發現了什麼...
If we find something...
我們該怎麼辦? 你知道,我應該向上匯報
what do we do? You know I'm supposed to report it.
我們是朋友,求你不要,好嗎?
Well, I'm... asking you not to. As a friend, okay?
天那...
Oh my...
呃...
Ugh...
我的天那
Oh, my God.
好吧...
Okay...
- 喬依怎樣? - 他很好啊
- How's Joey? - (Mary): He's good, you know.
成績單很不錯啊
Report card's off the charts.
他很想念你
But he misses the shit out of you.
哦.別了, 親愛的
Oh, come on, honestly.
他真的很想我? 當然了!
He really misses me? Of course he misses you!
我也很想你
Fuck, I miss you.
- 我也想你,寶貝 - 想到什麼程度?
- I miss you too, baby. - How much do you miss me?
非常想念你
Wide-open prairie miss you.
這個呢? 你想嗎?
What about these? You miss them?
哦,天那,你不知道我有多想念啊
Oh, Jesus, you have no idea how much I miss them.
等一下...
Hang on...
我必須回去,因為這個行動
I had to go back because this op
太早了.是排雷部隊發現的
was pretty early in the roto. But yeah, the DETs observed
有15到20名塔利班恐怖份子在那一區域活動
between 15 and 20 Talis moving across the field.
由於實力懸殊,他們不會輕易交火
Because of the force size, they didn't engage.
連隊司令部需要坐標
Company command requested the grid.
他們說,炮擊是最好的辦法
They called it in, artillery beat the shit out of them.
這裡應該有快速空中打擊力量,是吧?
There was some fast air in there as well, right?
是的,我相信有兩架A10s攻擊機
Yeah, I believe so. Two A10s.
- 他們要毀了這個地方?  - 這是他們擅長的
- And they destroyed the field? - That's what Warthogs do.
你看,問題來了.結果是
Well, see, this matters because, as it turns out,
這一地區由巴什 達烏德 可汗控制
the field is owned by Bashir Daoud Khan.
巴什 達烏德 可汗?
BDK?
看,巴什 達烏德 可汗把地租給農民...
See, BDK leases the field to the farmer, who's basically...
他像個奴隸.是嗎?
He's like a slave, right?
農民在地裡工作
The farmer works the field,
到了罌粟收穫的季節
then at the end of the poppy season,
他要上交5000美元
he's gotta hand over 5,000 USD.
不管怎樣,他們要留一點
Whatever he gets on top of that, he gets to keep,
大概800美元
which is probably like 800 bucks,
這是國家的平均水平
somewhere around the national average.
在這個特殊的案例裡
Now in this particular case,
塔利班來到田間
the Talis go running around the field,
政府軍把他們幹掉了
ISAF blows the shit out of it
莊稼也毀了.現在,那些農民
and the crop is ruined. And now, well, the farmer,
他們收入減少了
he's got less than Adam before the apple.
然後,巴什 達烏德 可汗來了,問道:"嘿,我的5000美元呢?"
Well, BDK shows up and goes, "Hello, where's my 5,000 USD?"
農民回答:"莊稼被毀了.你知道嗎?"
And the farmer says, "Well... the crop was ruined, you know?
不是我的責任
No fault of my own."
巴什 達烏德 可汗說:"我不管,我是魔鬼.我要我的5000美元"
BDK says, "I don't give a shit, I'm evil. I will have my $5,000.
你有很多時間來準備
And you have X amount of time to come up with it."
喔,這傢伙聽起來像是托尼女高音啊
Wow, this guy sounds like Tony Soprano.
是的,但是沒有調理的
Yeah, but without the therapist.
我們是阿富汗人.我們基本上都沒經過調理
We Afghans, we're not very big on therapy.
好吧,哪裡能找到這個
Alright, so why are we looking
農民? 他叫阿達姆 穆裡克
at this farmer? His name is Abdul Malik.
他父親的名字叫哈吉 穆裡克,沙漠之獅
His father's name is Haji Malik, Lion of the Desert.
他父親就是幽靈? 見鬼!
His father is the Ghost? Holy shit!
我們覺得這就是幽靈返回的原因
We think this is why the Ghost has returned,
要保護家族榮譽
to protect the honour of his family.
巴什 達烏德 可汗和幽靈之間還有些歷史淵源啊
There's some bad history between BDK and the Ghost.
我不想把事情搞亂.因為我需要幽靈
I don't want things to go haywire 'cause I want the Ghost,
我需要他為我們工作.因為他是一個很好的聯盟
I want him to work with us, 'cause he can be a powerful ally
促使我們能到達目的
for what we're trying to achieve down here,
也許我們能真正完成鬣狗大路的建設
maybe we'll actually get Hyena built.
那麼什麼時候合適呢?
So where do I fit in?
我覺得,日子很接近了,不是嗎?
Well, we think the date for payment is close, yeah?
兩三天吧.所以我需要村裡的眼線
Two-three days kinda thing. So I need eyes on that village,
我需要知道他們的出入時間
I need to know about the comings and goings,
和誰,幹什麼,所有一切
the who, the what, all that kind of thing.
我的狙擊手在這裡的活動範圍很大
I got my snipers spread all over the area of operation,
但是我可以重新部署,變更掃雷時間
but I can redeploy, rotate the DETs,
干兩天,停兩天,從今晚開始
two days on, two days off sort of thing, starting tonight.
好極了!
Outstanding!
- 你要確定時間嗎? - 不,謝謝
- You ever try a date? - No, thank you.
- 常規檢查 - 檢查
- Comm check. - Check.
正常
Right.
常規檢查 沃爾夫
Comm check to Wilf.
檢查!收到
Check! Roger you.
- 槍械彈夾檢查? - 檢查
- AKA training magnet? - Check.
- 槍械糟透了 - 檢查
- AKA I smell a shit. - Check.
槍械沒問題
AKA douchebag.
吥!
Brr!
看見什麼了嗎,坦克?
You seen anything, Tank?
- 沒有 - 好吧,休息一會兒
- Negative. - Alright, take a break.
收到
Roger that.
嘿,夥計
Hey, buds.
有什麼要告訴我的嗎?
Is there something you wanna tell me?
佩裡 科摩? 在戰區?
Perry Como? In a combat zone?
- 有點混亂 - 算了
- It was on shuffle. - Unacceptable.
完全不合適
Completely inappropriate.
你知道,我在想...
You know, I've been thinking about...
你剛說的關於武力改變一切
what you said about changing everything with one bullet.
你真的相信嗎?
You really believe that?
是的,我相信
Yeah, I believe that.
我在這兒,不是嗎?
I'm here, aren't I?
是的
Yeah, yeah.
看這個
Look at this.
這是什麼?
Okay, what the fuck is this?
我是個糟糕的舞者
I'm a terrible dancer.
你跳的真是太可怕了
You're an unbelievably bad dancer.
但我是個不錯的槍手,一直是
But I'm a great shot, and I've always been,
從我還是個孩子的時候
ever since I was a kid.
槍在我手裡也許不可靠
It might've been irresponsible to put a weapon in my hand,
但是很多人甚至連槍都沒有
but people would get hunting licences,
都可以得到打獵執照
they didn't even have a gun,
所以我可以代表他們打獵
just so that I could hunt on their behalf.
我喜歡玩高難度級的射擊遊戲
I used to shoot hard-to-shoot game,
桌上堆滿食物,時間很難度過
put food on people's tables when times were hard.
長官. 鮑曼上尉要見你們倆
Sir? Captain Bowman wants to see you both.
走吧
We're on.
阿爾法39,這裡是66號
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66 Bravo.
66號,這裡是阿爾法39
66 Bravo, Three Niner Alpha send, over.
66號,我們發現一個車隊
66 Bravo. We got a convoy heading our way, over.
阿爾法39,說具體一下
Three Niner Alpha, describe the convoy.
66號,有三輛車快速開過來
66 Bravo, three white Suburbans coming in fast.
看起來他們有武裝
Looks like they're up-armoured. Over.
阿爾法39,村子裡發生什麼了?
Three Niner Alpha, what's happening in the village?
66號,沒有任何動靜
66 Bravo, all is quiet, over.
他們還沒準備好,他們...見鬼!
They're not ready, they got no... Goddamn it!
- 發生什麼事情了? - 我不知道
- Okay, what's going on here? - I don't know yet.
讓大家就緒,收到
Get everyone up. Roger.
我靠.66號.我們發現兩個VIP重要人物在車裡
Holy shit. 66 Bravo, we got two VIPs exiting the vehicle.
一個40歲左右,黑色頭髮,小眼睛
First 40s, black hair, bad dye job, beady little eyes.
你能確認VIP是巴什 達烏德 可汗嗎?
Can he confirm VIP is BDK?
66號,阿爾法39號,是VIP 巴什 達烏德 可汗嗎? 你能確認嗎?
66 Bravo, Three Niner Alpha, is VIP BDK? Can you confirm?
66號,確認
66 Bravo confirming.
VIP是巴什 達烏德 可汗
VIP call sign Bravo Delta Kilo.
第二個人是哈米德 沃爾德 可汗
Second civ Hamid Walid Khan,
呼叫威士忌酒店
call sign Hotel Whisky Kilo.
阿爾法39,這裡是66號
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66 Bravo.
我們發現塔利班,四個人
We've got Taliban, counting four.
他和塔利班人在一起?
He's got Talis with him?
像巴什 達烏德 可汗這樣的傢伙兩邊通吃的
A guy like BDK plays both sides of the fence.
66號,阿爾法39,你有許可嗎?
66 Bravo, Three Niner Alpha, do you have clearance?
他們帶武器了嗎?
Are they carrying weapons?
週三到週五他和我們在一起
Wednesdays-Fridays he's with us
週二到週三他和塔利班在一起
Tuesdays-Thursdays, he's with the Talis,
休息日,他們販毒
and on days off, they're both running narcotics.
66號
66 Bravo,
不,他們沒有鞋帶武器,但是他們穿著整齊
negative, no weapons, but they're in costume.
黑色頭巾,黑衣人穿短衫
Black turbans, black man jams.
這些傢伙沒打算隱藏什麼
These guys are not even trying to hide who they are. Over.
66號,我們發現針對居民的敵對行動
66 Bravo, we have hostile action against civilians.
阿爾法39,請說清"敵對行動"
Three Niner Alpha, clarify "hostile action".
他們抓了孩子.一個小女孩兒
They're taking kids. Little girls.
阿爾法39,威脅程度緊急嗎?
Three Niner Alpha, do you have imminent threat, over?
66號,不
66 Bravo, negative,
但是他們把女孩兒
but they are grabbing little girls
抓到車裡了
and dragging them to their trucks.
可以開火嗎? 我已經準備就緒
Authorized to engage? I am getting ready to take the shot.
不,我來說
No, I'm stepping in.
66號,這裡是威士忌高爾夫9號.不要亂動
66 Bravo, this is Golf Niner Whisky. Sit tight, over.
什麼?! 幹掉他們!
The fuck?! Take them down!
我們不能行動,除非他們亮出武器
Unless they pull out weapons, we can't get involved.
- 66號,我可以干預的 - 威士忌高爾夫9號,不行
- 66 Bravo, I can intervene. - Golf Niner Whisky, negative.
除非你看到了武器,否則不可以
Unless you see a weapon, do not intervene.
66號,他們擄走了孩子
66 Bravo, they are taking little kids.
威士忌高爾夫9號,別輕舉妄動
Golf Niner Whisky, sit tight.
66號,明白.你在和我開玩笑嗎?
66 Bravo, clarify. Are you fucking kidding me?
威士忌高爾夫9號,除非你看到武器,否則不許行動
Golf Niner Whisky, unless you see a weapon, do not engage.
- 我們得做點什麼! - 你們只能觀望
- We gotta do something! - Your guys will stand down.
- 天啊! - 不能行動! 靠
- Jesus Christ! - Settle down, Warrant! Fuck.
我靠
F...uck.
- 你越權了! - 你為什麼不反駁?
- You're out of line, here! - Why didn't you override?
因為這是內部行動,是他們自己的事情!
'Cause it's an intel op, it's their call!
交戰規則,你知道的!
Rules of engagement. You know that!
- 那是犯罪啊! - 我們需要談談
- It's a fucking crime! - We need to talk.
不,你知道嗎? 我們很好,我們很好.嘿,米歇爾!
No, you know what? We're good, we're good. Hey, Mitchell!
米歇爾,那些女孩什麼樣的,8到10歲的孩子,嗯?
Mitchell, what are those girls, like 8, 10 years old, huh?
我們在那裡嗎? 她們會發生什麼?
And we just stand there? What's gonna happen to them, huh?
她們會被賣掉的,就是要發生在她們身上的事情
They're gonna be sold, that's what's gonna happen.
巴什 達烏德 可汗會把他們交給塔利班
BDK will hand them over to the Talis,
塔利班再把他們弄倒市場上去
the Talis will put them on the market.
不管怎樣,他們要抓大約5個,他們還會繼續
Whatever they get above 5, they're gonna keep,
但是巴什 達烏德 可汗也會得到他的5000美元.之後我就不知道了
but BDK will get his $5,000. And then I don't know,
她們最後的命運...
they're gonna end up in...
在迪拜結婚,糟糕的婚姻,也許更糟
some shitty marriage in Dubai, or worse,
她們也許會在福特 穆罕默德外面的妓院
they're gonna end up sucking dick in some brothel
為客人服務
outside of Fort McMurray.
你知道,這些我們不能干預嗎?
You know this and we don't intervene?
我們不能干預,因為我們沒有收到緊迫的威脅
We didn't intervene because we didn't have imminent threat.
這是交戰規則!
Those are the rules of engagement!
我必須遵守!
I had to make that call!
我們不能干預,因為巴什 達烏德 可汗被高層保護著
We didn't intervene because BDK is protected by a roof
有跡象表明和CIA高層有關!
on top of which is a great big fucking sign that reads CIA!
他是他們的人.現在,你想違背我們的將軍
He's their asset. Now, you wanna bring down our general
把整個戰鬥部隊搞亂?
and fuck up the entire battle group?
別客氣,去吧,打死他吧
Be my guest, go ahead, shoot him.
我們在這裡打的是什麼操蛋的戰爭啊?!
What kind of fucking war are we fighting here?!
哦,別這樣,這不是個簡單的戰爭!
Oh, come on, it's not one war!
這是完全不同的戰爭
It's a whole bunch of different wars.
至於我,就像是3D象棋裡的棋子
And mine, it's like a 3D chess game.
一半的時間,我都不知道
Half the time, I don't even know
和我下棋的對手是誰
who the fuck I'm playing against.
我們不打算在這裡玩遊戲!
We're not playing games here!
不,我們不是
No, we're not.
但是我們不在這裡,孩子們也是可以放飛風箏的
But we're not here so kids can fly kites either.
但是我們在這裡干他媽什麼呢?
Then what the fuck are we doing here?
我們在追索記錄
We are rolling back the clock
這次我們暗中佈局
and we are stacking the deck so this time,
所以那些喪心病狂的傢伙是贏不了的
the complete fucking crazies don't win.
哈吉,你得到了嗎? 是的,繼電器沒問題
Haji, did you get all of that? Yes, the relay was clear.
它還需要反應一會兒.它會找到巴達爾的
He's going to have to react. He will make badal.
巴達爾是塔利班另一個重要人物
Okay, badal is another one of those tribal pillars.
坐下吧
Come on, sit down.
請坐
Sit down.
巴達爾打算,就像...復仇.或者...
Badal basically means, like... revenge, or...
就像以眼還眼之類的事情
It's like an eye for an eye kinda thing.
這個更多的是關於榮譽
It's more about honour.
如果一個家庭的戶主不能重新奪回榮譽的話
If the leader of the family cannot restore honour to them,
那麼他必須離開,永遠離開
then he must leave, forever.
所以幽靈沒有選擇,他必須行動
So the Ghost has no choice. He must act.
事情是這樣的
Here's the thing.
在和蘇聯的戰爭裡,巴什 達烏德 可汗是幽靈的手下
BDK served under the Ghost in the war against the Russians.
事情是,蘇聯的直升機被擊落
Story goes that a Russian chopper went down
巴什 達烏德 可汗姦殺了飛行員.作為懲罰
and BDK ass-raped one of the pilots. And as punishment,
幽靈讓他在其他穆斯林面前很尷尬
the Ghost embarrassed him in front of the rest of the muj.
- 所以你明白, 巴達爾還在繼續 - 巴什 達烏德 可汗是個壞傢伙
- So you see, badal continues. - BDK is a bad guy
他需要被幹掉
and he needs to be brought down.
但是我們現在不能做, 但是幽靈可以.為了這個目的
Now we can't do it, but the Ghost can. To do that,
我們打算支持幽靈
we gotta boost the stature of the Ghost,
我們打算邀請幽靈
and we're gonna start by inviting the Ghost
參加鬣狗大路的開通儀式
to the ceremony for Hyena Road.
把他們放到一起,巴達爾沒問題
Put them together. Badal is possible.
我還打算提供一個安全屋
I'm also gonna offer up the safe house.
如果他們在鬣狗大路上見面
If they meet on Hyena Road,
那就是政治環境. 如果他們在安全屋見面,那就是私人恩怨
it's political. If they meet at the safe house, it's personal.
不管怎樣,他們都會交火的
Either way, there's gonna be fireworks.
好的,一會兒有架飛機要飛回坎大哈空軍基地,大約10到11英里.我要回去
Okay, there's a flight heading back to KAF in about 10-11 Mikes, I'm gonna hop on it.
我需要你去召集和幽靈的會議
I need you to set up a meeting with the Ghost,
在我們的安全屋裡
we'll do it at the safe house.
我需要你的隊伍負責安全保衛
And I need your team to scope out security
在儀式上和安全屋裡
at the ceremony site and at the safe house.
瑞恩...
Ryan...
別以為我不關心那些女孩兒.其實我想著呢
Don't think I don't feel for those girls, 'cause I do.
我會去盡力尋找她們的
And we'll do what we can to find them.
但是現在,最重要的是,我們需要幽靈
But right now, in the bigger picture, we need the Ghost.
特拉維斯說你在找我
Travis said you were looking for me.
是的...
Yeah...
好吧,我很抱歉.我失去了理智
Alright, look, I'm sorry, I lost my shit.
但你知道我的.你知道,大多數時間
But you know me. And you know that most of the time,
我為我做過的事情感到很驕傲
I'm proud about what we do here
也為我們將要做的事情感到很驕傲
and I'm proud about how we go about doing it,
但是...她們是孩子
but... those were kids.
如果我們不提供幫助,那麼我們做這些事情的意義在哪兒?
If we can't help them, what's the point of doing all this?
我不知道答案是什麼,也不知道到底哪個更值得
I don't... have an answer for that, and for what it's worth,
我同意你的觀點,但是這並不是...
I agree with you, but that's not, um...
我要見你的目的是
what I wanted to see you about.
嗯,你介意把門關上嗎?
Uh, do you mind just... closing the door?
嗯...
Uh...
坐,我給你看點東西
Have a seat, I just have to show you something.
這是什麼?
What's this?
嗯,是我們的孩子
Uh, that's our baby.
我猜是...塞浦路斯...
It was... Cyprus, I guess.
這是我見過最美麗的東西了
It's one of the most beautiful things I've ever seen.
最美麗的東西
The most beautiful thing.
這能改變不少事情,不是嗎?
This kind of changes things... doesn't it?
是的,這能改變很多事情
Yeah, yeah, it changes everything.
我覺得...你知道的,就我來說
I think that... you know, in terms of the brass,
我們會沒事的,因為我們離開後才會生
we're gonna be okay because it happened while we were on leave,
但是要想想今後的打算
but we gotta figure out what we're... gonna do.
想想今後的打算?
Figure out what we're gonna do?
我們有了孩子
We're gonna have a baby.
這是你想要的嗎?
Is that what you want?
是的,這當然是我想要的,比任何事情都重要
Yeah, of course it's what I want, more than anything.
好吧,我很高興
Okay, good, I'm glad.
你知道嗎,你搞的我快瘋了
You know, you're making me crazy.
我知道,我也把自己搞瘋了
I know, I'm making myself crazy.
- 你覺得我會怎麼想的? - 我不知道,我只是...
- What did you think I'd think? - I don't know, I just was...
我很緊張.我不知道
I was nervous. We didn't...
...事情發展的還不錯
...leave things very well.
過來,過來,嘿...
Come here, come here, come here. Hey...
我們有孩子了
We're gonna have a baby.
哦!你確定是我的嗎?
Oh! Oh! You sure it's mine?
戰術99號在基地
Niner Niner Tac on base.
靠! 又有一個掃雷隊員在鬣狗大路遭到襲擊
Cocks! Another IED hit out on Hyena.
一個反政府武裝人員,從喀布爾來的一個傢伙,開了幾槍?
One KIA. A guy out of Kabul, father of how many, Shorty?
- 5槍,長官 - 5槍,靠
- Five, sir. - Five. Fuck.
找到這些傢伙就像往牆上釘釘子一樣
Finding these pricks is like nailing Jell-O to the wall.
我們建造鬣狗大路,不能再有人員傷亡了
I cannot keep losing civilians if we're gonna get Hyena built.
如果我們想在那裡取勝的話...
And if we're gonna prevail down there...
鬣狗大路必須完成
Hyena's gotta go through.
我要去那兒,在地面上
I gotta get out there, on the ground,
用豹II式坦克
gotta get my Leopard 2s rolling,
把他們炸飛
and blow them fuckers out of their beds.
我要找到他們的彈藥庫
I gotta find their weapons caches,
我要幹掉他們的指揮中心
I gotta fuck with their command and control
我不能從直升飛機上做這件事
and I cannot do that bouncing around in goddamn helicopters.
這樣動靜太大,皮特
That's a kinetic imperative, Pete.
我需要你的人用安靜點的方式去做
I'm gonna need a little help from you non-kinetic types.
我需要你的人去那裡,按你的方式
I need you effects guys going there and work your magic.
明白,長官.我們正在為此努力
Understood, sir. We are working on it.
我的阿富汗內線告訴我,巴什 達烏德 可汗是事情的幕後指使
My Afghan guys tell me that BDK's behind all of this shit.
安全形勢越惡化
The more the security situation deteriorates,
他們得到的錢越多
the more money he's making out of all the gravel trucks,
還有一些其他感興趣的東西
all the other stuff he's into us for.
- 可惡的傢伙 - 如果不是因為他
- Fucking horrible little man. - If he was out of the picture,
完成鬣狗大路會容易很多
getting Hyena through would be a hell of a lot easier.
他被收拾.我是不會為之流淚的
He gets knocked of his perch, I would not weep.
明白.長官
Understood, sir.
我聽說幽靈回來了
I hear the Ghost's back.
- 是的,長官 - 有威脅嗎?
- Yes, sir. - See a threat?
恰恰相反.我覺得他是個很有利的同盟
Just the opposite. I think he could be a powerful ally.
我不管你怎麼幹
I don't care how you do it,
要保證我的人不會受傷
just make sure my civilians aren't getting hit
他們每次都是開輛破卡車過去
every time they drive a fucking truck down there.
- 明白,長官 - 謝謝,皮特
- Understood, sir. - Thanks, Pete.
哈吉,你在幹什麼呢?
Haji, what the fuck are you doing?
什麼? 你都無法通過玻璃看東西了
What? You can't see out of these things!
這裡沒什麼可看的啊
There's nothing to see.
不,不是這樣的,不!
No, not the way they are, no!
好吧...聯絡幽靈,繼續那個會議
Okay... Get in touch with the Ghost, the meeting's on.
你得到許可了?
You have approval?
尋求原諒總比徵得同意更好些
It's always better to ask for forgiveness than permission,
你知道的
you know that.
我們在安全屋見
We'll meet him at the safe house.
這個房子有個重要特點
This house has a key feature.
它是我們的安全屋
It's our asset, a safe house.
我們會在山脊處設置觀察員
We'll set up our OP here, at the summit of the saddle back ridge.
那裡可以看清山兩邊的情況
That'll give us clear line of sight to both sides of the hill:
這裡是安全屋
here, at the safe house,
這裡是慶祝儀式的地點
and here, where the ceremony's gonna take place.
- 範圍是多少? - 很合適
- What's the range? - It's comfortable,
山兩邊1150米,750米
1, 150, 750 metres both sides of the hill.
那關於撤離地點呢?
And what about extraction?
我們從後面撤離,經過葡萄地
We'll exfil down the back side, through the grape fields
他們在鬣狗大路上接我們
and get picked up en route Hyena.
安全屋做什麼用?
How's this house gonna play?
這個不知道
That's unknown.
有一個提議是讓幽靈和巴什 達烏德 可汗接洽
There's an offer out to the Ghost and BDK to show.
他們可能在安全屋進行
Intel thinks they'll show up either at the safe house
也可能在儀式上
or at the ceremony,
所以我們兩邊都要照看
so we need eyes on both.
這是一次重要的行動,所以我來指揮
This is a tricky op, so I'll take lead.
沃爾夫,你跟著我
Wilf, you'll stand this one down.
好的,讓我們準備一下吧
Alright, let's gear up.
我很感謝你能見我
I would like to thank you for meeting with me.
他說:"這是我的榮幸"
He says, "The honour is mine."
他說:"我來這裡感到很驚訝
He says, "I'm surprised to be here.
我來這裡很多次了"
I used to come to this house many times."
他問:"你知道這裡是誰的房子嗎?"
He's asking, "Do you know who used to own this house?"
穆勒 奧瑪
Mullah Omar.
他的耳朵保住了,眼睛卻沒了
He saved his ears, but he lost his eye.
- 這是什麼意思? - 同樣的
- What does that mean? - Same same.
- 什麼同樣的? - 同樣的
- Same same what? - Same same, same same.
不管什麼原因你要使用這裡
If you ever need to use this house for whatever reason,
請儘管用
it's yours.
那天在潘吉發生了一件事
There was an event in Panjaway the other day,
哈吉 巴巴村
the village of Haji Baba.
有兩個女孩兒被搶走了
Two little girls were taking out of the arms or their father.
他說:"你為什麼不來找我"
He says, "Why have you come to me?"
因為女孩兒是被巴什 達烏德 可汗搶走的
Because the little girls were taken by Bashir Daoud Khan.
我的將軍是一個富有同情心的人
My general is a compassionate man.
他是普什圖瓦裡的學生
He's a student of Pashtunwali.
他想幫助你,幫助阿富汗
And he would like to help you, to help all Afghans,
幫助哈吉 巴巴村
to help the village of Haji Baba.
他很希望你能收下這個禮物
And he would be very honoured if you would accept this gift:
5000美元
5,000 US dollars.
他也很希望你能參加
He will also be honoured if you would attend
鬣狗大路的開通儀式
the ceremony for Hyena Road.
他說:"為什麼是我? 我只是個種葡萄的"
He's saying, "Why me? I'm a simple grape farmer."
他理解,但是你是出席
He understands this, but your presence would do him
讓他感到十分的榮幸
a great honour as an elder of the region.
"還有誰去?"
"Who else will be there?"
巴什 達烏德 可汗
Bashir Daoud Khan.
"我在巴什還是個孩子的時候我就認識他"
"I have known this man Bashir since he was a boy."
"他做了很丟臉的事情
"He brought great dishonour to our cause,
我親自懲罰了他"
and he was punished by my own hands."
"感謝將軍的好意
"Thank your general for his kindness,
我能參加也很榮幸"
and it will be my honour to attend."
他說:"小雞討厭你"
He says, "The chicken hates you."
是的,哈吉, 是我
Yeah, Haji, it's me.
是的...
Yeah...
我正看著他走過小山
I'm watching him walk up the side of a mountain.
是的,他打算參加
Yeah, he says he's gonna show up,
但是我感覺他袖子裡有什麼東西
but I got the feeling he's got something up his sleeve,
所以,我需要你特別留意
so I'm gonna need you to get your eyes and ears out there,
看看能發現什麼,好嗎?
see what you can learn, okay?
是的...
Yeah...
好的,帶上東西,出發
Okay, let's get our gear, we're going.
喔! 當地肉類?
Whoa! Local meat?
神聖的神父...
Heavenly Father...
請保護這些小女孩兒
Please protect those little girls.
照看他們,把他們帶回家
Watch over them and bring them home.
嘿...
Hi...
嘿,聽著,我不是很確定,也不十分清楚
Hi, listen, I'm not sure I was entirely clear about all this,
所以我得說出來
so I want to spell it out.
我非常想...
I'd like it very much if, um...
你能嫁給我嗎,鮑曼上尉
you'd marry me, Captain Bowman.
我也非常希望如此. 桑德斯准尉
I would also like that very much, Warrant Officer Sanders.
好的,我要走了.我們要出發了.我還有裝備
Okay, I gotta go. We're heading out. I gotta kit up.
哦,為什麼我不能幫你拿裝備呢
Oh, why don't I... help you with that kit.
哦...我們太瘋狂了
Oh... we're crazy.
去它的什麼證明
Fucking certifiable.
小心點
Be careful.
我保證
I promise.
他讓我發瘋!
You're driving me crazy!
上帝啊...
My God...
哦,靠...
Oh, fucking...
嘿,珍
Hey, Jen.
嘿,你覺得該如何演繹?
Hey, hey. So how do you think this is gonna play out?
哦,很難說,變數很大
Oh, hard to say, a lot of variables.
如果計劃有把握,我們就贏了
If the plan holds, we're golden.
也許有變化,誰知道呢
Anything shifts, who knows.
戰術99號已經上路,長官
We got Niner Niner Tac en route, ma'am.
好的,夥計.將軍已經上路
Okay, buddy. Here we go, general's on his way.
你要去儀式地點?
You were down at the ceremony site?
是的,要去的.一群亂七八糟的人
Yeah, on my way here. Usual motley crew.
到處是山羊,漫山遍野的糞便
Goats everywhere, shit all over the goddamn place.
你知道我想看見什麼嗎?
You know what I'd like to see?
我想看見這個國家能舉辦奧運會
I'd like to see this country host the Olympics,
那才了不起
that would be awesome.
66號,阿爾法39,報告
66, Three Niner Alpha, sitrep.
阿爾法39,66號,視野很好
Three Niner Alpha, 66, good visual,
可以很清楚的看見兩邊
clear line of sight both sides, over.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, roger.
66號,看見戰術99號了
66, Niner Niner Tac in sight, 1 click out.
我確認是戰術99號
I confirm Niner Niner Tac in sight.
我確認沒有VIP出現
I bet you not one VIP's gonna be there.
他們不會來的
They're not gonna show.
哦,我覺得他們會來的,長官.這對他們很重要
Oh, I think they'll be there, sir. It's important to them.
25美元,我賭他們不來
25 bucks says they're a no show.
好的,長官
You're on, sir.
我喜歡你的熱情,肖蒂,靠!
I love your enthusiasm, Shorty. Fuck!
出發!
Go, go, go, go!
快走!
Move your ass out!
- 快點,夥計們,出發!
- Come on gentlemen, let's go! - Move!
66號,戰術99號到達地點
66, Niner Niner Tac has landed, over.
你欠我25美元.你知道嗎?
You're gonna owe me 25 bucks. You realize that, don't you?
我是個樂觀主義者,長官
I'm an optimist, sir.
你是個傻瓜,肖蒂
You're a fucking idiot, Shorty.
收到,長官
Roger that, sir.
阿爾法39,我是66號
Three Niner Alpha, 66,
在路上發現車隊
I have convoy in sight on approach road, over.
阿爾法39,是白色的SUV嗎? 確認
Three Niner Alpha, white SUVs? Confirm.
66號,確認,三輛白色SUV,帶武裝的
66, confirming, three white SUVs, up-armoured, over.
66號,車隊轉彎向北進發
66, convoy has turned north off approach road,
向安全屋的方向去了
heading in direction of safe house, over.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, acknowledged.
好的,大家開始行動.巴什 達烏德 可汗準備行動了
Okay, everybody, we're on. BDK's going for it.
幽靈和巴什 達烏德 可汗要在安全屋見面
The Ghost and BDK will meet at the safe house,
不在儀式地點
not at the ceremony site,
所以會演變成私人恩怨
so this is probably gonna get personal.
你拿到繼電器了嗎?
You got that relay for me at ASIC?
連通了,長官.可以了
You're hooked up now, sir, go ahead.
啊,祖魯11號,這裡是威士忌高爾夫9號,請求
Ah, One One Zulu, this is Golf Niner Whisky requesting
手機陷阱,魁北克坐標3669-8537
cellphone trap at grid Quebec Quebec 3669-8537, over.
威士忌高爾夫9號,這裡是祖魯11號
Golf Niner Whisky, this is One One Zulu.
你運氣不錯,我們很擅長這個
You're in luck, we got a high asset
在你說的坐標區域上進行設置.運行陷阱...可以了
sitting on top of your grid marker. Running traps... now.
阿爾法39,66號,車隊停下了
Three Niner Alpha, 66, convoy has stopped, over.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, roger.
威士忌高爾夫9號,這裡是祖魯11號.我們設置了通信陷阱
Golf Niner Whisky, One One Zulu. We have a trap.
三個信號.要同時做嗎?
Three signals. You want them all up?
祖魯11號.威士忌高爾夫9號,不是的
One One Zulu, Golf Niner Whisky, negative.
你能一個一個的弄嗎?
Can you just feed them to us one by one, over?
他們在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
他們在監聽他們的手機
He's turning their cellphones into listening devices,
但是別問我怎麼實現的,我不懂
but don't ask me how, I have no idea.
祖魯11號,第一個陷阱來了
One One Zulu, first trap coming at ya.
祖魯11號,我是威士忌高爾夫9號,不
One One Zulu, Golf Niner Whisky, negative,
你可以暫停這個陷阱了
you can drop that trap, over.
祖魯11號,收到.第二個陷阱來了
One One Zulu, good copy. Number two coming at ya.
是的
Yeah.
祖魯11號,我是威士忌高爾夫9號,這就是我們要的人
One One Zulu, Golf Niner Whisky, that's our guy,
呼叫66號,那就是巴什 達烏德 可汗
call sign Bravo Delta Kilo, that's BDK.
感謝你的幫助,掛了
Thanks for your help. Out.
阿爾法39,我是66號,前門已經打開
Three Niner Alpha, 66, front door is opening,
幽靈走出來了
call sign Ghost is stepping out.
幽靈獨自一人
Call sign Ghost is alone.
他不應該獨自一人.他應該有同伴的
He shouldn't be alone. He should have guys with him.
那麼這是什麼意思?
So what does that mean?
幽靈說,巴什讓他們的
The Ghost says that Bashir has insulted
家族蒙羞
the honour of his family.
對於一個年輕人,一個學生,這是罪大惡極
For a young man, a former student, this is a great sin.
巴什說,他的兒子阿卜杜勒欠他5000美元
Bashir says that his son Abdul owed him 5,000 US dollars.
幽靈說,他會給他5000美元
The Ghost says he has just given him 5,000 US dollars.
巴什感謝了他
Bashir thanks him
還說這就解決了錢的問題
and says this will satisfy the question of the money.
幽靈說,是的
The Ghost says yes,
但是債務還沒結束
but the debt is not yet resolved.
他要他的孫女,小女孩兒
He wants his grandchildren, the little girls
被抓走了. 他需她們回來
that were taken. He wants them returned.
巴什說,這不可能
Bashir says this is impossible.
孩子走了,幽靈應該知道這些
The girls are gone, and the Ghost should know this.
- 這太操蛋了 - 收到
- This is so fucked up. - Copy that.
巴什說,他的兒子哈密德失蹤了
Bashir says that his son Hamid is missing.
"他的兒子?" 怎麼還有這樣的事情?
"His son"? How the fuck did I not have this intel?
好吧,巴什生氣了
Alright, Bashir is angry.
他說,他也希望他的兒子能回來
He says he wants his son returned to him.
他說,他要見他的兒子
He says that he wants to see his son.
幽靈說,"那你應該"
The Ghost says, "And so you shall."
天那,阿爾法39,這裡是66號,我看見一個人頭
Jesus. Three Niner Alpha, 66, I have a head,
在地上有一個人頭
a human fucking head lying on the ground.
靠
Fuck.
那是他的兒子,呼叫威士忌酒店
It's the son, call sign Hotel Whisky Kilo.
我靠,巴什 達烏德 可汗該急了
Shit, shit, shit, BDK is gonna react.
好吧,他們不能交火
Okay, look, they must not engage.
66號,我是阿爾法39,巴什 達烏德 可汗在幹什麼?
66, Three Niner Alpha, what is BDK doing?
有敵對意圖嗎?
Do you have hostile intent?
我們發現武器
We got a weapon.
66號,巴什有武器
66, call sign Bravo Delta Kilo has a weapon.
已經威脅到幽靈
Hostile intent towards civ call sign Ghost
開干吧
Fucking light him up.
66號,我是威士忌高爾夫9號,別開槍
66, Golf Niner Whisky, do not take that shot.
- 他要行動 - 我來說
- He has clearance. - I'm overriding.
66號,威士忌高爾夫9號,你不理解
66, Gold Niner Whisky, you don't understand.
66號,我理解什麼是緊迫威脅
66, I understand imminent threat.
- 斃了這個混蛋 - 我要開火.
- Hit him, for fuck's sakes. - Am engaging. Wait out.
確認,向上23度
Confirm. Up 23.
向右2度,收到
Right 2. Roger.
66號,威士忌高爾夫9號,瑞恩,不要開槍!
66, Golf Niner Whisky, Ryan, please, do not take that shot!
他有企圖,他不需要你的許可
He has intent. He doesn't need your okay.
就緒
Standby.
瑞恩,不要開槍
Ryan, please don't do this.
這是巴達爾的工作方式.這也是幽靈想要的
This is how badal works. This is what the Ghost wants.
就緒
Send it.
瑞恩,求你了!
Ryan, please!
擊中目標
Good hit.
好的,夥計們,我們收拾一下
Alright, guys, let's pack up.
將軍,我們該走了
General, we have to go.
戰術99號,這裡是零點,建議撤離
Niner Niner Tac, this is Zero advising exfil.
戰術99號開始出發
Niner Niner Tac on the move.
戰術99號正在撤離.所有人撤離
Niner Niner Tac exfiling now, all birds in escort.
66號,這裡是威士忌高爾夫9號
66, Golf Niner Whisky.
你知道你剛才幹了什麼嗎?
You have any idea what you just done?!
66號,是的,我認為我知道
66, yeah, I think I do.
我這裡有居民受到了緊迫威脅,我進行了干預
I had imminent threat towards a civilian, I intervened.
是的,你的確干預了.66號
Yeah, you did intervene, 66,
你什麼都不知道!
in something you know nothing about!
後退,米歇爾
Back off, Mitchell.
66好,阿爾法39.繼續撤離
66, Three Niner Alpha, continue to rendezvous.
你剛剛搞砸了!
You just fucked up!
你打你的戰爭,上尉,我干我的
You fight your war, Captain, I'll fight mine.
66號,威士忌高爾夫9號,幽靈想
66, Golf Niner Whisky, call sign Ghost was seeking
死得很有榮耀...
an honourable death, and you just...
你卻阻止了這一切!
you took it away from him!
- 我們剛剛救了他 - 這不是你們該做的!
- We saved his life. - It wasn't yours to save!
現在,他沒有價值了! 你知道嗎? 他沒有用了!
Now, he's got nothing! You understand that? He has nothing!
夠了.上尉,這是我的事情.你退後
That's enough, Captain. This is my CP. You will back off.
向你敬禮
Salaam Alaikum.
- 他在幹什麼? - 我不知道
- What's he doing? - I don't know.
在想我們剛剛如何救了他的?
Think he knows we just saved his bacon?
我認為比這個複雜很多
I think it might be more complicated than that.
怎麼可能?
How? What can possibly
- 我靠 - 臥倒!
- Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck! - Down, down!
他們是從哪裡來的?
Where the fuck did they come from?
從安全屋離開的人一定叫了增援
The guys from the safe house must've called for backup.
我右邊有5到10個人
I got five to ten on the right!
掩護!
Covering!
哦,特拉維斯,靠!
Oh, Travis, fuck!
希基,脫掉!
Hickey, strip the classifieds!
阿爾法39,這裡是66號,發生交火,很多敵人
Three Niner Alpha, 66, contact, multiple insurgents.
有一人受傷
One times VSA, vital signs absent.
部隊發生戰鬥
Troop's in contact.
我們遭到來自兩翼的攻擊!
We're taking effective fire both flanks!
阿爾法39,收到.有多少敵人?
Three Niner Alpha, roger. How many insurgents, over?
靠...
Fuck...
這裡是66號,大概有20到30人
66, two zero to three zero hostiles.
他們從哪裡來的?
The fuck they come from?
我們的無人機距離多遠?
How far away are the birds?
他們大概需要30分鐘
They're at least 30 minutes out. Moved back
退到戰術99號那裡去.好的可以去戰術指揮中心
to exfil Niner Niner Tac. Shit. Okay, get on to the TOC,
退守到馬薩山丘地面部隊那裡去
get a QRF rolling out of Massum Ghar.
我們試圖撤離!向葡萄地進發
They're trying to break contact! Move in the grape hunt,
我們在那裡可以進行防守!
we'll strong-point from there, over!
阿爾法39,收到.我們會催促空中支持和地面部隊
Three Niner Alpha, roger. We're pushing for air and QRF,
但是你們要堅持一下
but you're gonna have to hang in there.
- 掩護! - 掩護! 換子彈!
- Covering! - Covering! Changing mags!
66號,我們要保護一個平民
66, be advised, we have a civilian under our protection.
是幽靈
Call sign Ghost.
我操?
What the fuck?
- 我們要帶他走 - 從不放棄! 走吧!
- We gotta leave him. - Never! Let's go!
掩護!
Covering!
快走!
Go, go, go!
掩護!
Covering!
- 放下他 - 掩護!
- Drop him, drop him. - Covering!
快走!
Go, go, go!
帶上他!
Take him!
掩護!
Covering!
換子彈! 掩護!
Changing mags! Covering!
換子彈!
Changing mags!
帶上希基! 快走! 進屋去!
Take Hickey! Go! Get to the door!
走啊!
Go, go, go!
快點! 走!
Come on! Go, go!
啊!
Ah!
- 阿爾法39,這裡是66號 - 我很抱歉...
- Three Niner Alpha, this is 66. - I'm sorry...
我們在葡萄地防守
We're strong-pointing from a grape hut.
我們子彈快沒了.我們被包圍了
We're running low on ammo. We're being surrounded.
地面部隊情況如何?
What's your QRF status?
嗯..阿爾法39,地面部隊還有5英里
Uh... Three Niner Alpha, QRF is one five Mikes out,
你要堅持啊
you gotta hang in there.
別讓他們告訴我,主啊,求你了,活不了了
Don't let them take us, Lord, please, Jesus, not alive,
他們要幹掉我們
they're gonna fucking skin us.
巴達爾?
Badal?
無人機的信息來了
We've got a UAV above them now, ma'am.
- 好的,顯示出來 - 打到屏幕上
- Okay, put it up. - On screen.
哦,天那.這麼多敵人啊
Oh, my God, there's dozens of them.
66號,阿爾法39,請報告情況
66, Three Niner Alpha, sitrep please.
阿爾法39,66號...
Three Niner Alpha, 66...
很多恐怖分子全面進攻
Multiple insurgents in force on all points.
請求火力打擊, 魁北克坐標
Am requesting fire mission at grid Quebec Quebec
3312-8976
3312-8976.
不,瑞恩.不,你那裡太危險了
No, Ryan, no, you are danger close.
高爾夫羅密歐4號,這裡是66號
Golf Four Romeo, this is 66.
不,瑞恩,正好就在你的位置
No, Ryan, it's right on top of you.
準備和敵人同歸已盡
Gonna take out everybody including himself.
66號,高爾夫羅密歐4號,收到
66, Golf Four Romeo, send.
高爾夫羅密歐4號,阿爾法39號，取消行動
Golf Four Romeo, Three Niner Alpha, override fire mission.
66號,授權,非常危險
66, authorize, danger close.
向魁北克坐標3312-8976開火
Fire for effect at grid Quebec Quebec 3312-8976.
高爾夫羅密歐4號,收到.準備開火
Golf Four Romeo, acknowledged. Fire mission up.
阿爾法39.取消開火命令
Three Niner Alpha, rescind fire order!
取消魁北克坐標的命令! 阿爾法39!
Cancel fire order grid Quebec Quebec! Three Niner Alpha!
求你了.天那,瑞恩,不要這樣做...
Please, Jesus, Ryan, don't do this. Please don't do...
66號授權
66 authorizes.
準備射擊魁北克坐標3312-8976
Fire for effect at grid Quebec Quebec 3312-8976.
我要做一個父親了
I'm gonna be a father.
你明白嗎?
You understand?
你知道我要說什麼嗎?
You understand what I'm trying to say?
開火!
Fire!
66號,高爾夫羅密歐4號.發射完畢.你有9秒鐘時間
66, Golf Four Romeo. Shot over. You got 9 seconds.
阿爾法39,這裡是66號
Three Niner Alpha, this is 66.
阿爾法39,收到
Three Niner Alpha, acknowledged.
66號,我很抱歉,寶貝
66, I'm sorry, baby.
前進!
Go! Go, go!
我右邊有2個!
I got two to my left!
是誰給你的消息?
So who is it that gave you this tip?
- 我舅舅 - 是啊?
- My uncle. - Really?
阿富汗的成年男人都是你舅舅?
Is every single adult male in Afghanistan your uncle?
- 是的 - 太神奇了
- Yes. - Amazing.
我要去喀布爾待一段時間
I'm going to Kabul for a while.
去看看你的家人?
To see your family?
坎大哈最近有些瘋狂
Kandahar is a bit crazy right now.
是啊,注意安全
Yeah. Be safe.
你回來後聯繫我
Call me when you're back.
靠,我要遲到了
Fuck, I'm gonna be late.
這個瑞恩,他是你的朋友
This man Ryan, he was your friend.
是的...他是
Yeah... Yeah, he was.
我在這裡沒有很多朋友
I don't have too many friends here.
你有我啊.我是你的朋友
You have me. I'm your friend.
是的,你是
Yeah, you are.
轉身!
Turn!
準備放下!
Prepare to lower... Lower!
還原!
Recover!
轉身!
Turn!
亞歷山大是過去三年裡
Alexander the Great fought a counter-insurgency
阿富汗偉大的反恐先鋒
in Afghanistan that lasted almost three years.
經過這麼多年
And by the end of those years,
他酗酒,還有些偏執
he was drinking heavily and completely paranoid.
一天夜裡,他和一個忠實的朋友
One night, he got into a row
克萊圖斯發生了爭吵
with a guy named Cleitus the Black, a loyal friend.
克萊圖斯控告了他
Cleitus accused him of certain things
亞歷山大給了他胸口一槍
and Alexander threw a spear into his heart.
他看著自己的朋友死去,自己也失去了理智
As he watched his friend die, he lost his mind.
五年後,亞歷山大也死了
Five years later, Alexander was dead.
阿富汗人說:
As the Afghans say:
你也許能得到時鐘
you might have the clocks,
但你留不住時間
but we've got the time.